evolutionary fws lambda with
hexagonal architecture um
um
hello hello nice to meet you likewise yeah okay
so now it's your time so you can start at any time
perfect fantastic thank you very much for the
introduction uh and sorry a bit for my voice
i have a bit of code so uh it would be a bit
weird my voice but don't worry i will do my
best that you you will be able to enjoy the talk
so today i'm going to talk about aws lambda but
specifically how to modularize your code in order
to have a let's say a system that would be able to
follow the drifts that uh the business would uh it
is looking for because in reality every business
is evolving and is changing direction and we
have some ways as architects and developers
that will allow us to follow their direction
and improve and evolve our architecture
following uh the right business
direction my name is luca magdalera
i'm a principal solution architect at aws i'm
an international speaker and an o'reilly author
so let's start with defining what evolutionary
architectures are and directly from the book
building evolutionary architecture that if you
didn't read uh trust me is a really great book um
you can see that evolution architecture supports
guided and incremental changes and i think here
the key part is the incremental changes because
uh more often than not when we have like new
features that are coming or there are new requests
from from the business they are quite chunky so
they start to say i would like to connect your
system with this third party and then evolve
uh the um computation adding new functionalities
and anything what you what you need to think
about every time is trying to break down those
uh let's say complex requests in smaller units
that are deliverable and that's why evolution
architecture can really help us to achieve that
so i think everyone at least once uh have to
deal with the three years after architecture
the free tier software architecture is composed
by three layers the first one is a presentation
layer you have dynamic application layer where
all the business logic leaves and then you have
a data layer where basically you store your your
data but the problem when you deal with this kind
of architecture that is still valid uh i i see a
lot of uh let's say uh that's still a lot of um
um implementation with with pretty architecture
nowadays the problem is that in the long run what
usually happens is there is a leak of domain
between the data layer and presentation layer
towards the application layer what it means is
basically sometimes when you need to implement
a feature and you are under pressure or time
constraints uh you start to take this code and
and start to uh let's say do some create some
tech debt uh the problem is more often than not
is difficult then to remember about the tech depth
or to uh let's say fix the tech depth and sooner
rather than later the application layer became
obliterated of information that shouldn't leave in
that specific layer the other thing that um i have
experienced firsthand was moving some workloads
to to aws london so imagine that you have for
instance your container living on aws ccs or you
have your application running in a virtual machine
in this case ec2 and you want to move everything
to lambda the complexity if the code is not well
structured is extracting a portion of a domain and
move to the london now this despite it could uh
let's say seem simple a simple problem to solve uh
it results that is not especially when you don't
plan upfront on creating some code that is modular
enough for being decoupled and then you will be
able to easily move between different compute
services the third point uh that they want to make
is uh more often than not when you're looking for
example or lambdas or maybe you have some numbers
that are written uh similar to uh to this one um
you find this kind of code and usually what you
have is inside your hand lambda handler you have
like all these code that contains basically the
um retrieval of uh the the request from the body
uh in this case of a post of a post request and
then you have like submit candidate p that is
basically the um function uh in the middle of
this image and candidate info so those two um
those two basically functions what they do is
submit candidate p is communicating with the
database instead candidate info is containing
information around the domain so what we uh
want to store inside the database but as you can
see here there is a mix and match of uh incoming
requests parsing validation uh and then you have
like in integration with infrastructure and so
so forth if we want to evolve this kind of code it
becomes complicated mainly because we need them to
test every single bit end to end to make sure that
we didn't introduce any bug and that is a very uh
let's say challenging problem because when you
are working in large system if you have multiple
of those implementation you you risk that you
jeopardize your velocity and throughput because
you basically are living in a code that is very
tightly coupled together so examiner architecture
is trying to solve that alistar cockburn that is
the creator of alexander architecture but also
co-sign the agile manifesto so it's a person that
really give a lot to to the software community
created the examiner architecture in with one
thing in mind trying to find a way to decouple uh
the business logic from the environment where it's
running and that basically uh provides some nice
side effects the first one is that you can drive
your application uh in different ways it could
be like a batch script it could be a unit test it
could be uh let's say a request from a service but
because you modularized very well your code you
don't risk to pollute the business logic uh in in
a way that then became uh unflexible and therefore
you need to spend a lot of time to evolve it
um the other thing uh that i want to to
focus is understanding deeply how hexagonal
architecture works so let's take a look to the
anatomy of an examiner attraction so the first
if you want layer or exit learning this in
this case is the domain logic the main logic
is basically what you want to
achieve inside your aws london
the beauty of of applying examiner architecture on
lambda is that because lambda by design is is not
let's say a very complex environment so you have
like a small amount of logic if you encapsulate
very well your domain logic it became easier
to test and evolve it without too many problems
second layer is the ports and ports are basically
the entry point for the external world towards the
domain logic and also are the way how the domain
logic is interacting with the external world
and finally you have adapters
adapters as the name suggests
uh is uh uh taken from the idea of the adapter
pattern the basically is a way that uh two
different contracts are communicating together the
role of the adapters is basically becoming your
anti-corruption layer between the external world
and your business logic and is also translating
what is coming from the external world towards the
internal world the communication between domain
logic and adapters is happening always through
ports this architecture is also called port and
adapter so you can hear hexagon architecture
okay airport adapter they mean the same thing
the um interesting part of these is the ports
could be uh depends on the language that they
are using it could be just an interface and
therefore an adapter is implementing an interface
for communicating with domain logic or it could be
like in the example that we are going to see uh a
a function i'm going to use node.js with uh es6 so
javascript and not typescript but we type language
type language like java or c-sharp or
uh typescript you can use interfaces the
other part that you need to be aware on the exact
architecture is that you have primary actors the
primary actors are the ones that are communicating
with your aws lambda in this case inside your
examiner architecture what they are it could be
another microservice it could be a client it could
be a message inside the queue because the lambda
can be called synchronously or asynchronously
and then you can have secondary actors
that basically are the actors that are
used by our code for uh i don't know for
instance retrieving information from a
database consuming a service a third party
service or adding a message in a queue so those
are basically the key point on how you are going
to to structure your exaggerator architecture that
obviously is valid for aws lambda but it could be
valid also with the container or with the virtual
machine bear in mind currently the focus of this
talk will be on lambda because uh i think these
architectures specifically can really shine inside
the serverless paradigm the benefit and drawbacks
so benefit is the business logic is agnostic to
the outside world and that is absolutely great
because it means that we have we can evolve it and
change it without affecting the rest of the code
it's independent from external service therefore
for the business logic it doesn't matter if we
are using a sql database or no sql database what
it matters for the business logic is that it's
going to request some information to a repository
and then the adapter encapsulate all the logic
for interacting with that repository and that
allows you to really evolve your code in a way
that it's a better for for everyone then um it's
easier to test and test in isolation especially
and we will see more in this talk and
finally is reducing the technical debt
the fact that you spend a bit of time upfront
defining those boundaries and those modules
will allow you to run faster in the long run
at the same time on the pitfalls or drawbacks
you need to spend more time thinking on
building multiple layers because you need
to create adapters ports and business logic and
in the original implementation defined by alistar
cockburn there weren't too many references on
how to structure your business logic that is not
uh necessarily a negative thing but it means that
you have an opportunity for uh let's say use your
knowledge and your style for encapsulating
better the code inside your business logic
so if by now you're thinking okay why an accident
why not not another shape alistar cockburn is
providing also the answer for that the hexagon is
not the meaning of how many how many sides we need
uh in a shape but it's just a good way to
represent the complexity that a specific
service could be could interact with before we
just rectangles we didn't have enough space for
drawing all the interaction that the service could
be exposed to and nowadays with microservices this
is becoming even more important uh because um you
you may have multiple interaction as a primary or
secondary actors so i prepared a demo uh on
on this and what we are going to see is this
is a very simple demo but provides you the idea
of what we can really do with this approach
so first of all you have an api gateway
that is exposing an api the api is
basically every time you call this rest api
you trigger an aws lambda that is called stock
converter and as the name suggests what expects
is a stock id and when you receive the stock id
is going to retrieve the value of the stock id
from the stocks table that is a dynamodb table
and then is going to call a third party service
where it is going to retrieve real-time all the
currencies and then when it has those two piece
informations the business logic is going to apply
the currencies to the stock value and return back
the value of uh the stock in multiple currencies
that's basically what we're going to see and
when we see in slow motion uh how the interaction
would work so first of all you will have an http
request the adapter will pick the http request
and through the port is going to
communicate with the business logic
passing the stock id then the business logic
as the first thing is going to call a port
and saying to the port please retrieve
this uh stock id and the port knows that
has to communicate without an adapter then
the adapter is communicating with dynamodb
because it is encapsulating inside it all the
information related to dynamodb and then the
business logic triggers another action that is
calling through an adapter as a through a port
another adapter that is communicating with the
currency service that is a third party service
and then it returns everything so let's go back to
uh our ide and let's try to see what we have here
okay so this is the structure of my project as
you can see here i have a folder for adapters
domain and ports um usually you it depends
how you want to structure you can potentially
divide also this part per domain and have like one
business domain that contains sport adapters and
and business logic uh in my opinion because
we are working with lambda we are already
reducing the scope of of the domain so in
theory you should be able to structure the
code with just adapters domain ports but it's
completely up to you how you want to do that
the uh if we see how the the uh logi the the code
works based on the logic that i just explained
this is the entry point of our lambda okay so
we have like literally not much here because
what we have is the lamb that is retrieving the
stock id from the url and then is passing this
information to this adapter that is called that
has a function called get stock request get stock
request once again in this case is a primary
adapter this is coming from the primary actor
and what it does is just calling it doesn't have
to do validation on anything it's just calling
a a function for inside a port and is when he
receives the response it will drop the uh final
um with a response to the uh to the client if
we go inside then the port the port as i said
before but is important to iterate is as simple as
a function in javascript if you have typescript or
any other type language you can use an interface
so the port basically what it does in this case
is exposing a function and is
communicating with a business logic
why we're doing this because in this case now we
have the adapter that is completely decoupled from
the business logic therefore we can evolve those
two entities as as we want without risking to uh
let's say having a side effect that are bubbling
between between different layers as long the
contours will remain the same we are in a good
shape so in the business logic uh once again here
we have all the currencies that they want to uh to
use so in this case is american dollars canadian
dollars australian dollars uh but the important
thing is that i have other two uh action to do
first i call this repository port that will
communicate with a repository in this case
dynamodb uh through the adapter uh for retrieving
the stock id when i retrieve the stock id
i will then call the currencies therefore a third
party service for doing so and then i will apply
the logic that i explained before for uh let's say
applying the currency to the original stock value
great so um let's go for the
repository so the repository is a port
and as a port uh it it just has a function
that calls an adapter the adapter is get
stockman this is a secondary adapter because it's
calling is handled basically by our aws function
um and here as you can see what we have
is all the information related on how to
retrieve a specific item from the database
if i want to change the schema if i want
to change the way i'm i'm querying the
database or the way how i'm i don't know
writing data in the database in a hypothetical
thing the only thing that they need to change is
this partner and that is one of the benefit
of working with this with this approach
now if we go back to our business logic the other
interesting part is what we are going to do with
uh the currencies and the currencies has these
get that this port is called get currency data
and then it goes to to retrieve the currencies
here we have a point-to-point communication with
a third party service and that's it so we retrieve
the information we send back to the uh to the
business logic and business logic knows how to
do by now you understand that the business logic
doesn't know how who requested this information
it could be api gateway it could be unit test it
doesn't matter for the business logic and it
doesn't care even if it's communicating with
a sql or nosql database or where is the endpoint
that we are retrieving information therefore we
encapsulated very well the business logic
and can evolve as we prefer now let's
play a game let's think about a new scenario
you deploy this aws lambda in a production and
your service starts to get a lot of traction
so people are extremely interesting to that
and what happens then is um that you uh basically
start to see uh some uh errors coming out from
your uh lambda because the third party service
is not capable to cope up with the traffic uh
the request per second that you have uh from your
service you need to figure out a way to solve that
obviously it's a third party service so you cannot
say listen can you increase by i don't know 10x
the amount of requests that they have because they
have let's say their own architecture and they or
they um their own uh things to to to handle
therefore usually you have a limited amount
of requests that you can you can have okay so the
other alternative is that you handle on your side
so in this case what we can do instead of doing is
using this adapter we can i created a new adapter
that is called um currency converter with cache
and here as you can see i have exactly the same
signature so the same function the same contract
but what they have added here is a elastic cache
with redis that is a service available in aws
for using a managed version of redis cluster
and the um beauty of this approach is that
basically i'm implementing a cache inside
my my logic so here the logic would be first thing
first check inside radius if i stored any currency
and if i do return back to the client without
making any call to um to the third party service
and to a certain extent this is great because that
means i'm offloading dramatically all the traffic
that is going to the third party service because
i'm using the cash if the cash is evicted is empty
uh i have the possibility to call the third
party service and then i immediately store the
information retrieved from the third party service
inside radis and i set an eviction policy of 22nd
after 20 seconds automatically redis will evict
the cash and you can go ahead with let's say
querying again the third party
service for training fresh data
this approach scaled pretty well because as you
can imagine if you have 10 landers that are let's
say querying the database simultaneously then
you go uh you go with these 10 lambdas you are
going to hit the vast majority of the time red
is more than third party service so that is great
okay so we have seen uh uh how to
structure the code in ojs and how it works
now another example that i want to add on
this uh scenario again so imagine now that
instead of having a lambda the team that was
working on this was starting from a container
and therefore docker container in this case so in
this case this is the code that i need to do as
you can see here i have the same folders with
the same files okay nothing nothing different
so i copy and paste those inside this new
application i have a different obviously entry
point because this is my web server in node called
fastify it's a well-known framework in node.js
and uh the interesting part is this
the entry point is exactly the same
what it means though it means that basically
imagine that you have a crowd application where
you are creating updating writing and reading uh
and deleting elements inside the database i will
have obviously multiple of those methods so if
we structure the code in a modular fashion we can
extract portion of the code and move to a lambda
without any problem and that is the power of this
approach we can also move between compute services
uh very easily because we modularize the code in a
way that would allow us to have this flexibility
to evolve our code based on the business needs
okay so let's go back to the slides and let's
start to think about other use cases because
that those are some of them but there are more so
the first one is testing and isolation as i said
before now the business logic is well encapsulated
and that means potentially you can have a faster
feedback loop when you're writing code imagine
that you are writing your code and you have your
business logic is well isolated you can even
separate how you're running your code in a way
that when you connect to a database unless you are
often changing schema it is not going to happen
very often uh you that code will be solid so you
need you don't need to test but the business logic
would evolve and therefore what you can do is
running dividing the test for the adapters and the
business logic in your uh development environment
and then testing more often the business logic
or the part that is evolving more and therefore
having a faster turnaround on the rest and then
doing more extensive tests uh when you are about
to open up a request or whatever but this really
speed up the way how you are doing testing the
cache inside pattern is the one that we have seen
before so we implement the redis cache and it's
very similar so you have the service that is it
in your lambda and then the land is communicating
with the database in order to offload or a third
party service in order to offload the request
because maybe some of the queries are always the
same you can add the cache and depends obviously
from database to database that you're going to
use if you're using dynamo you can use dax
that is another service that is let's say
fully managed and allows you to have a cache
layer in front of dynamo but if if you want
you can use elastic cache with uh radis and it's
completely up to you on memory db that is a new
service that we launched very recently the other
thing is imagine that you want to change the
trigger so the way how your application works so
instead of having an api gateway that is calling
the lambda function now you want to have an
asynchronous model where the api gateway is
storing the request directly to uh sqs so a queue
and then the the lambda is trigger uh in batches
so it takes like few elements inside the queue
start to process them and then behind the scene
the client is starting to have um a request a
polling mechanism or a socket for understanding
when the computation is accomplished so those
kind of things are easy to implement because
in this case the only change that you're going to
make as long as the computation remains the same
is that the primary adapter so you basically
change the adapter in a way that instead of
receiving the request from api gateway has to
extract the data from the from sqs and that is
great because it means that basically we don't
have to change anything on our business logic
another scenario is service migration so imagine
that you have a lamb that is communicating with
a self-managed mobile database and at some
point you realize that you spend too much
time on maintaining this database and you want
to move to a managed database version so in this
case it could be aws documentability that is
let's say powering one with the bb in the scene
the uh beauty of this approach is that like
once again you go you're going to change
just the adapters for the piece of logic
doesn't care if it's mongodb or document b
and also you can apply certain migration
patterns that you wouldn't be able to do so
so despite you obviously when you do
immigration or database you need to find a way
to migrate the data but then on the business
logic side you can use for instance a branch
by abstraction pattern that basically is allowing
you to run those two things in parallel and maybe
for a certain period of time just to make sure
that all the data are synchronized properly
you uh check on mongodb the responses that are
coming from document db and then when you are
confident you just uh move ahead but that is a
really great use case the other thing is modern
web application modernization so imagine
that you have your monolithic architecture
and you start to divide that by different
subdomains and then those domains usually in in
software architecture as some new one
described multiple times this is called
a modular monolate when you have a monolithic code
base that is divided by sub domains what you can
do is basically preparing yourself for migrating
to microservices and that is going to help
because when you divide with examiner architecture
your code the immutable sub domains then is easy
to extract portion in multiple microservices
and the same thing is going to happen when we do
from microservices to london the interesting
approach here for me is this one uh so the
fact that you have a microservice with multiple
obviously uh endpoints that are running there
you can extract some of them in lambdas based on
the volumetric that you're going to receive so for
instance if your microservice has a lot of reads
but not many writes and many delete and update
what you could do potentially as a first step is
uh instead of going with four lambdas one per uh
h rest verb or http verb you are going to have
one for read that has a different scale button
compared to the others and one for the other
three actions and then when you see that there
is a real need for let's say moving away and
from maintaining these three uh and let's say
other http verb in the same lambda you can slowly
but study migrating but you gain you're gaining
immediately the serverless benefit because you
move away from uh having a managed container
then finally hybrid strategies and that is
an interesting one right because sometimes
you have some workloads that require your code
to run in uh two environments maybe on-prem and
uh on on the cloud and an example is if
you have your uh examiner architecture
what you could do potentially is running your
aws lambda in aws and then have the same business
logic running on k native okay native is a
kubernetes offering for serverless that could run
um everywhere to be honest the beauty
of this approach is that you write once
the business logic and then you basically start to
spread the um so the test is just once and you you
are really making sure that everything is working
the only thing that you are going to change
probably are the adapters and as long as you
maintain the same contract the only effort that
you have is maintaining the adapters in aws and in
kenya that is in my opinion absolutely fantastic
finally there is one real let's say niche
and esoteric if you want architecture that i'm
quite interested on but it's still early days
it's called patholith architecture the concept
of patholith architecture is basically having
the possibility to work with microservices at
the development time but deploy in smaller units
when you go on uh on the cloud in this case
so what it means is that i'm developing a
microservice and my another team is developing
another one and because they're in the same domain
i can merge them at compile time and
send um all together inside a unique
piece to instance or whatever um this is still
let's say early days and there are quite a few
researches around that but it's something that i i
wanted to add just to give you an idea that where
also exactly architecture can shine i've seen an
implementation that uh is using a library node.js
library called microlib that what it does is using
these and even going further where you can reload
at runtime uh your code directly inside your
accident that is uh quite interesting obviously
still early days so uh don't take this tomorrow
introduction but definitely keep an eye on it
so obviously uh exactly architecture started um
was let's say released in 2005 so a big time ago
uh and uh since then there were some evolution
so the first one is uh this one is this uh onion
architecture uh that uh what it does is solving
the problem that we were describing before trying
to create a more structured and opinionated uh
business logic uh and the same was uh it happened
in 2020 2012 where um uncle bob uh they introduced
the clean architecture that is very dissimilar
uh to to the online one but with different
uh let's say entities uh and uh constructs
the interesting part here for me is uh if we're
talking about uh with a monolithic code base i see
the need of um structuring the better the business
logic totally i can see that uh on the lambda in
theory if you structure properly your lambdas and
you're not going to have a very complex lambdas
using just hexagonal architecture as i've shown
you uh during this uh session i think would be
more than enough because otherwise you start
to go too granular and you know um talking with
a customer uh it was telling me we we went to
the clean architecture route for microservices
and it was a proliferation of files that at the
end was difficult to manage in the long run and
i totally agree so you need to find the right
balance and the right trade-off despite yes there
are some other uh more structured architectures
but i believe that exaggerated architecture
as i showed you uh it should be enough for
your serverless workers so now the question
uh probably after this um this session is uh
is this the definitive architecture that aws
encourage for uh developing uh lambda the answer
is it depends as a good architect i couldn't say
yes or no because uh it really depends from
the context architecture is always based on
trade-offs it doesn't exist the right or wrong
but the only thing that exists is that your
context has some requirements and based on the
requirements you take a decision now what i see
uh really uh shining this architecture is when
for instance you have a workload that has to
evolve uh during the time imagine for instance
that you are developing a software as a service
or you have an internal product that you need to
maintain for years and years and years definitely
investing a bit of time on structuring your code
with the exact architecture can can really help
on the other side if you have uh for
instance a project that should stay
online for i don't know a couple of
months because maybe it's an event
starting with the exact architecture probably
is an overkill same when you have like a service
that is not doing much is maybe a service that is
just i don't know uh calling a a third party or uh
basically it's a proxy between two elements
starting with the exact architecture probably
probably is an overkill but there are uh let's
say situation where it can really shine for me the
important thing that for me is it should be that
your main takeaway is try to understand deeply
your context find the what are the characteristics
of your architecture and then based on that take
the decision if uh external architecture could
help you on your serverless workload or not
so just to wrap up uh so we have seen that
we have a strong separation of concern with
the external architecture then we have seen
that infrastructure is fully decoupled from
the business logic so we can evolve both
in parallel and potentially with let's say
different people or even you can evolve
taking different direction without any problem
exactly architecture is easy to test thanks to
the two characteristics that i mentioned before
and finally there are many use cases
where that are simplified when we use
uh etc architecture therefore if for any given
reason you know that uh some of the use cases
that i mentioned are going to happen no fear
not because you will be able to cover that
uh i gather in this life that we share later on
quite a few links uh you can find the demo that
i showed you uh on gitla on github and you have
also i wrote an article based on on this example
what i described uh that is available in the
compute blog uh of aws and you can read basically
what i described during this talk and then i
have you have a bunch of other uh links like
uh the original article on exam architecture the
only architecture clean architecture and so on
that's it for me thank you very much i'm more
than happy to jump on uh some questions and
if you want to contact me because later on
you have other questions or anything that is
my email so feel free to contact me anytime i
respond to everyone so uh thank you very much
okay thanks luke hey wait wait
thanks zuka well that's very informational
and knowledgeable uh presents okay so
the next one will go to the qna session
if you haven't asked the question yet please go to
the slider and and post your question and you can
upload your favorite one so that we can
see that more clearly i'll choose that one
let me see
okay uh look how can you could you see
the the slide on my screen okay cool
yeah great so let me choose the first one okay the
first one is does the hexagonal architecture must
go with aws london the way it decoupled protein
adapters from business lodges seems to fit in
on premise service as well okay you can go
yeah totally uh so the exact architecture it
doesn't work only with lambda it works with
containers it works with any type of code
is an architecture button right i uh i think
exactly architecture was well discussed for
for a long long long time inside the the community
and this is not let's say a novel thing but i i
thought that currently i didn't see many talking
about exact architecture properly on aws lambda
and i think with the ws lambda where more often
than not uh because it's a small entity we tend to
just write everything inside inside the handler is
a good pattern for helping uh the development
of of serverless let's say architectures
creating a wealth structure mechanism that at
least is well known and also uh is easy to to
implement so definitely you can run on premise you
can run a container you can run wherever you want
okay okay thank you and yeah let's uh actually
this is my first time too here we can mix
uh we can mix hexagon architecture with
lambda okay that's very interesting
and we can see lots more potentials
for aws lander okay next one okay so
is the currency converter service through
it safe i'm a serverless tfc member i know
the answer but i guess attended attendees
once you know it no less against my office
i i believe so uh so i i don't believe it would
be uh not safe so yes i think the answer is yes
yeah cool that's a sweet show and comfort
and it comes yeah good answer the next one
can we take hexagonal architecture as the idea
of clean architecture in cloud-based service
yeah totally uh you can use these
architecture for lambda for whatever they
they the other two architectures that i mentioned
like onion and clean are i mentioned them mainly
because sometimes when you go online and you start
to research around the external architecture they
they bubble up uh very often and people start
to say oh this is an exacto architecture
and it's true technically speaking they are
exotic architecture however is not the original
implementation are more structured version of the
hexagon architecture uh that are taking all the
characteristics of example architecture and then
adding on top of that a more structured business
logic yeah i agree then all those architectures
they share some common correct curricular
receipts yeah okay next one so someone is
very curious about could you explain more
about the pathways architecture um yeah
and explore curriculum characteristics
yeah so the name patholet is coming from one of
our colleagues in aws um adrian uh cockroft uh
that is that was the uh chief architect in netflix
he migrated basically the netflix architecture
towards um cloud and microservices uh and now is
working in aws uh on the sustainability uh part
so his idea basically is trying to uh decouple um
the try to reduce let's say the complexity on the
infrastructure or maintaining infrastructure but
maintaining the same flexibility that you have
with microservices at development time and the
idea is it's pretty interesting if you think about
that because compute and resources are becoming
extremely cheap uh so if we are capable to say
okay instead of having a proliferation of micro
services all over my accounts i start to have
less of them more if you want infrastructure wise
macro services and then i although i i have a very
granular approach on on the way how i'm developing
and then the basically the the the infrastructure
part is completely decoupled uh by the development
phase so i don't map one theme to one microservice
or one api to my microservices whatever it
is i map a domain to a bunch of microservices
i have the benefit of using microservices they're
for distributed teams that are empowered to make
changes atomically but on the other side i have
less to maintain on the infrastructure because
there are less things that could go wrong uh
everything maybe a specific um a specific domain
could live inside the same machine and therefore
the communication is even uh not affected by
latency and other things so the concept is pretty
interesting uh i think is it may break some other
uh ideas that in the community are well known by
now but uh it's uh it's definitely an interesting
architecture and i'm keeping an eye on it because
i want to see how it's going to evolve yeah thank
you that's cool okay i think we still have some
time okay so let me go through the next question
cool the next one is when we apply line the lambda
to make the it make the micro service what things
will meet problem and the risk yeah so at the end
uh lambda is a think about that is running inside
a container so if you have already a containerized
micro service uh let's say you should have too
many troubles obviously it depends what you're
doing inside the microservice if you're doing
some special things uh like using specific uh um
i don't know extensions or anything uh you need
to apply carefully them on on lambda wherever it's
totally doable uh but that that is not a problem
the beauty of of lambda is usually that you try to
uh split up in a modular fashion what you have in
a micro service so in the example that was making
before having a crowd operation where you are
decoupling basically uh the read from the right
operation inside your system you can have for
instance two lambdas you can even even add more
if you want to scale in a different fashion um the
the risk i would say um on top of my head i
would say that the main risk that you may have
is some uh patterns that are not manageable by
you so for instance uh if uh you say uh i know
up front that uh i'm going to have um i don't
know uh five millions of requests per second
uh on on a microservice then you can say
okay i uh prepare everything upfront uh in my
containers and i warm up everything i add more
machine than needed uh and so on so forth with
lambda you have a server you have a feature that
allows you to have a pre worm of your lambda
but then you are living inside your the constraint
basically provided by the service because it's
this fully managed service of a compute part
and therefore you can increase the amount of
lambda you can have per account uh but definitely
there are some quotas that you need to be aware
and you need to when you design your workload be
very aware to understand how your traffic pattern
should be implemented inside the serverless
solution i think that is the main thing but
what you can do in a server in microservices
you can do also in a serverless application
yes thank you yeah i agree that um however no
matter how you uh what kind of a technique you use
you are using make sure you understand its limits
and its ability yeah okay next one the live demo
is really cool and well explained i'm curious how
to explain the advantage of the architecture that
is easy that is easy to understand for business
people yeah that's quite a big challenge yeah
uh thanks for uh for the praise on on the demo
thanks for that uh so uh i think there are a
few points so the first one would be um the
possibility to uh to evolve their needs faster
they less introduction of uh production
bugs that already are a big advantage uh and
the fact that you can really drift uh the
direction of a system quickly because yes there
is an initial investment but if in the code that
you have seen i really have a small amount of code
that working as a solo developer or even in a team
it became extremely easy to atomically say okay
we need to make this feature you take care about
the adapter i take care about the business logic
so you can really parallelize the work in a
nice way and if you are disciplinated enough
or maintaining this structure uh during the the
life cycle of the project you would be able really
to uh follow and expand the need of things and
probably the first thing could be uh innovation
so if you want to try one thing quickly you just
try that and you uh let's say dropping away inside
your code that is modular enough that we you can
immediately test it and then if it doesn't work
you can remove at the same speed so you have
innovation you have a faster turnaround on new
features and you have less bugs in production
i think just these three characteristics should
be enough for for business people yeah i agree
that look i think the only thing the business
people only care about is could you deliver your
product or products uh more frequently more faster
and more safely yeah that's all are we concerned
about cool the final one or finally the final one
is could you list some main aspects that make
you choose hexagonal architecture from others
um yes so the the main choice for me is when
um when i have a project they need to maintain
in the long run so for instance imagine that
you want to run a quick poc just to a proof of
concept just to make sure that uh your idea
is working that probably i wouldn't go with
uh with uh an external architecture but then when
you want to really implement your code and you are
working on a product that has to you are going to
maintain for six months one year whatever is where
usually i will i will look into it especially
for serverless because in other architecture
so if you in for other more monolithical
code bases like for container whatever
there are plenty of architectures out there
that you can use the beauty of this is that
you you can um really test in isolation
certain parts and and the fact that you can
uh um um let's say structure the code in a very
modular fashion so for me in the lambda if uh or
already by design it shouldn't have too much
scope inside the lambda so it's very easy to do
to create but if we had also examined architecture
evolving that became easier uh and uh and so for
me the the rule of thumb would be is it is it
code that i have to thrown away after a while or
is it the code that i am not going to use for for
long term or is this very very small action that i
need to do inside my alarm that probably i won't
use external architecture for the rest of the
use cases yes say it's a bit more uh investment
but it's not definitely that it's going to take
twice the time for uh for writing in london
yeah i agree i think every investment has
its own risk and you can always start small
but if you want to go farther maybe you can
consider other things like hexagonal architecture
and you want to have a more scalability and you
want to have more um do you want to involve
your models quickly maybe you can consider
london and hexagonal architecture okay so thank
you luka again and very happy to have you here